A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Buenos Aires, Argentina Field Office Files FA562
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Buenos Aires, Argentina Field Office Files
1959-1975
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA562
2.62 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Alphabetical (A-Z)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation maintained an office in Buenos Aires, Argentina from 1962-1975. Throughout the course of the Buenos Aires office's history, the Foundation's Argentina program focused on supporting projects and initiatives involved with science and technology, education, social science research and training, agricultural development, industrial and trade development, public and private management and administration, and population.
After the Foundation closed the Buenos Aires office in 1975, its Argentina programming became absorbed under its broader Andean Region and Southern Cone program aims. The Andean Region and Southern Cone office moved from Lima, Peru to Santiago Chile, in 1991.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains correspondence, reports, consultants and regional files.
- Consultants, 1959-1962 (Box 1)
- Consultants, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
- Consultants, 1965 (Box 1)
- Consultants, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
- Consultants, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
- Consultants, 1970-1972 (Box 1)
- Contact (Taquini) -- General Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 1)
- Demography (Regional) -- General, 1969-1972 (Box 1)
- Education (Regional) -- General, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
- Foreign Area Training Fellowships (Regional) -- General, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
- Fundaciones Nacionales en la Republica Argentina, 1968 September-November (Box 1)
- Institute of International Education (Regional) -- General, 1966-1975 (Box 1)
- Latin American Teaching Fellowships, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
- Meeting of Program Advisors in Education (Regional), 1972-1973 (Box 2)
- Miguens Report, 1969 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Project Proposal -- Women in Latin America, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- Paraguay (Regional), 1966-1973 (Box 2)
- Population FY1972, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
- Rural Sociology -- Argentina, 1972 (Box 2)
- Social Sciences in Argentina, 1971 (Box 2)
- Social Sciences (Regional), 1969-1970 (Box 2)
- Travel and Study Awards -- General Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
- University of Buenos Aires (Argentina) -- General, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
- University of Cordoba (Argentina) -- General, 1961-1971 (Box 2)
- University of Cordoba -- Fertility Project, 1971 (Box 2)
- University of La Plata (Argentina) -- General, 1962-1972 (Box 2)
- University of La Plata -- Di Tella -- C.I.A.P., 1970-1972 (Box 2)
- Uruguay (Regional) -- General, 1968-1972 (Box 2)
- Uruguay -- Secondary Science Education, 1969-1973 (Box 2)